Phillip: So how do you go about
managing innovation and change?
It’s all about planning, monitoring,
and using review techniques.
Maddy: There are lots of different models you
can use to help you manage innovation and change.
In this video we’re going to take a look
at three common models: Gantt Charts,
the PDSA model, and the SMART model.
Phillip: Gantt Charts
A Gantt chart is a form of bar chart that
represents each activity in a project.
This could be installing a new IT system or
training teams in new work methods, and the
chart represents the amount of time each
activity will take to complete, and the tasks
that need to be done for that completion.
Maddy: By creating a Gantt Chart, you are
mapping out everything that needs to be done
to achieve the change or innovation identifying
all the tasks and activities, what they
rely on, and when they need to be completed.
For example, a major activity in an
innovation project might be training everyone
in a team to use a new computer system.
However, this can’t happen until
that system has been installed.
But is installing the system the
first thing that needs to be done?
Phillip: It might not be, does the organisation’s
IT system need to give their approval first?
Are there going to have to be other changes
applied to the whole computer system
before the new system can be installed?
A Gantt Chart can help identify the critical
tasks that need to be completed to keep the
innovation project on track and on schedule.
Maddy: PDSA
The next model we are going to look at is PDSA
and this stands for: Plan, Do, Study, Act.
It’s a model for testing the changes you
want to implement before fully committing,
and can help you spot potential problem
areas before you start the roll-out.
Let’s have a look at the four stages in order:
• Phillip: Plan – before the change takes
place, you need to spend time planning it,
so you know what you’re doing, and when
• Maddy: Do – make the change
• Phillip: Study – compare data from before or after
the change; for example, if you’re trying a new
sales strategy, are you attracting new customers?
• Maddy: Act – proceed with fully implementing
the change, or go back to the planning stage
The PDSA model also provides you with three
questions that can help to identify what the
change you’re actually making is going to be:
• What are we trying to accomplish?
- This is called the aims statement.
• Phillip: How will we know if
the change is an improvement?
- This helps you identify what
data you need to collect.
• Maddy: What change can we make
that will result in improvement?
-This is where you identify the change itself.
Phillip: SMART
Our final model is SMART, and this
stands for: Specific, Measurable,
Attainable, Realistic, Time bound.
Maddy: SMART is a model you might have heard of
before as it is used in many different fields.
It helps to specify the targets and objectives
you’re trying to achieve through the innovation.
So, let’s look at each part
of SMART in more detail.
• Phillip: Specific –This means you
clearly define the goal you’re pursuing.
You should avoid making the goal
too general, as this makes it harder
to know if it’s been achieved.
• Maddy: Measurable – You should define how
you’ll know that the goal has been achieved.
You can see that it’s easier to do that with
a specific goal, rather than a general goal.
• Phillip: Attainable – The goal
you’ve defined has to be possible!
There isn’t much point in putting
time and energy behind a goal that
has little chance of being achieved.
• Maddy: Realistic – A goal may be possible
but still not actually likely to be achieved.
Make sure it’s realistic that the
goal can actually be attained.
• Phillip: Time-bound – there should be a
clear timeline for achieving the goal.
This helps focus activity and makes
the plan more likely to succeed.
Maddy: SMART allows you to really think
about the kinds of goals that you want to
achieve in order to successfully innovate.
Phillip: There’s a wealth of information
online about these methods, along with
many others and some may feel more
useful and relevant directly to you.
So, take the time to do some additional
research and to deepen your knowledge
on managing innovation and change.